# **Konstantinos** Pappas

Email: konstantinospapppas@gmail.com Phone: +34 657124026 +30 6978912292 Address: C. de Atocha 70 201812 Madrid **LinkedIn:** www.linkedin.com/in/kpappas **GitHub:** www.github.com/Kostas-Pappas

Web Page: link

## Summary

I am quantitative researcher with a background in finance and a passion for data science. I love exploring new technologies, frameworks. applications and A.I. related papers. I have been known to rant about hackathons, Kaggle competitions, my Trello board being overwhelming and NFL.

If a task entails financial data and involves quantitative modeling and data analysis, I am up for the challenge.

### Languages

**ENGLISH**: Professional Proficiency

SPANISH: Advanced User **GERMAN: Basic User GREEK: Native Speaker** 

### Certifications

- CFA Level 3 candidate (May 2022)
- FRM Part 1

### Other

Military Service - Completed (2016-2017)

#### **Conference Presentations:**

"The Determinants of option market liquidity"

8th National Conference of the Financial Engineering and Banking Society Athens 19.12.2017

## **Work Experience**

#### **Quantitative Research - ETS Asset Management Factory | Jan2020-**

Conducting quantitative research for equities team. Developing investment strategies, researching trading signals, developing proprietary backtester.

Projects worked on: building factor investing strategy, short selection algorithm(ML model using data augmented data ),research for ESG adaptation of our strategies.

### Capital Markets Analyst - ColmexPro | Aug 2018 - April 2019

Monitoring trading room exposure, manage market counterparty risk, and execute trades for clients. I managed to automate emails and excel reports using Bloomberg API, SQL, Python and VBA.

#### Financial Products Intern - Alpha bank S.A. |Feb2018 - May 2018

Analyzing deposit products and transactions pricing using VBA, Access and SQL. Conducting pricing checks and data quality checks of the databases.

#### Junior Consultant - GSDN Consultants S.A. |Jan2017 -Feb 2018

Main duties involved audit, tax, cost accounting procedures and preparing presentation and reports

#### **Junior Accountant - GSDN Consultants S.A.** | Jun 2015 - Nov 2015

Conducting financial analysis and cost accounting & preparing financial and budget reports.

### **Education**

#### **Data Science Bootcamp**

#### Ubiqum Code Academy(Barcelona)| May 2019-Nov2019

Ubiqum offers a rigorous 6-month data science bootcamp simulating work environment using agile. I worked on Data Analysis projects using Machine Learning and Deep Learning tools in Python & R and cloud services (AWS, GCP) building and deploying models, dashboards and communicating insights in real world case studies.

#### **Msc Applied Mathematics**

University of Athens | 2017 - 2018

Major: Operations Research & Financial Mathematics

Stochastic Mathematics Optimization methods, Computational Methods (MatLab & R), Data Analysis, Derivative pricing

**Bsc Business Administration** 

Athens University of Economics and Business | 2010-2015

Major: Finance and Accounting

### **Programming Skills**

Python: pandas, numpy, scipy, scikitlearn, tensorflow, pytorch,, nltk., PySpark,

**R**: h2o, mlr, shiny, tidyverse, ggplot2

DataBases: MySQL, postgreSQL, SQL Server, BigQuerry

Other technologies I have worked with: AWS, GCP, Docker, Kubernetes,

GitLab